{
   "questions": [
      {
         "questionId": 1,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Who is the only other player other than Jamal Murray to score 50 on less than 24 field goal attempts?",
         "answer": "Bob Cousy",
         "choices": [
            "Michael Jordan",
            "Lebron James",
            "Bob Cousy",
            "Kareem Abdul Jabbar"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 2,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Who are the two players to have 25 point halves in a single playoff series?",
         "answer": "Jamal Murray/Allen Iverson",
         "choices": [
            "Jamal Murray/Allen Iverson",
            "James Harden/Russel Westbrook",
            "Michael Jordan/Kobe Bryant",
            "Steph Curry/Lebron James"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 3,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who was the NBA’s first ever unanimous mvp?",
         "answer": "Steph Curry",
         "choices": [
            "Michael Jordan",
            "Shaquille O’Neal",
            "LeBron James",
            "Steph Curry"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 5,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who was the youngest player to score 10,000 points?",
         "answer": "LeBron James",
         "choices": [
            "Kobe Bryant",
            "LeBron James",
            "Michael Jordan",
            "Kevin Durant"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 7,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who scored the most points in a single NBA game?",
         "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain",
         "choices": [
            "Kobe Bryant",
            "Wilt Chamberlain",
            "James Harden",
            "Michael Jordan"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 8,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What team has the worst W-L percentage in NBA history?",
         "answer": "Minnesota Timberwolves",
         "choices": [
            "Minnesota Timberwolves",
            "Phoenix Suns",
            "Cleveland Cavaliers",
            "New York Knicks"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 9,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who has the most Finals MVP’s?",
         "answer": "Michael Jordan",
         "choices": [
            "Kareem Abdul Jabbar",
            "Magic Johnson",
            "Shaquille O’Neal",
            "Michael Jordan"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 10,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What franchise has the most HOF’s to date?",
         "answer": "Boston Celtics",
         "choices": [
            "Los Angeles Lakers",
            "Chicago Bulls",
            "Boston Celtics",
            "San Antonio Spurs"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 12,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What was the name of Toronto’s first NBA team?",
         "answer": "Toronto Huskies",
         "choices": [
            "Toronto Raptors",
            "Toronto Huskies",
            "Toronto Knickerbokers",
            "Toronto Grizzlies"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 13,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who are the only two players in NBA history to average a triple double in a single season?",
         "answer": "Oscar Robertson/Russell Westbrook",
         "choices": [
            "Oscar Robertson/Lebron James",
            "Magic Johnson/Russel Westbrook",
            "Luka Doncic/James Harden",
            "Oscar Robertson/Russell Westbrook"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 14,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who holds the record for most assists in a single game?",
         "answer": "Scott Skiles- 30",
         "choices": [
            "Kevin Porter- 29",
            "Magic Johnson- 32",
            "John Stockton- 31",
            "Scott Skiles- 30"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 15,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What team drafted Kobe Bryant?",
         "answer": "Charlotte Hornets",
         "choices": [
            "Charlotte Hornets",
            "Los Angeles Lakers",
            "Minnesota Timberwolves",
            "Los Angeles Clippers"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 16,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What team did Kobe Bryant score 81 points against?",
         "answer": "Toronto Raptors",
         "choices": [
            "Dallas Mavericks",
            "Portland Trailblazers",
            "Toronto Raptors",
            "Washington Wizards"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 17,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who holds the record for most steals in a playoff game?",
         "answer": "Allen Iverson",
         "choices": [
            "Manu Ginobli",
            "Scottie Pippen",
            "Allen Iverson",
            "Gary Payton"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 18,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Draymond Green was selected with the ____ pick in the NBA draft.",
         "answer": "35th",
         "choices": [
            "5th",
            "20th",
            "35th",
            "60th"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 19,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Youngest player to ever record a triple double in NBA history?",
         "answer": "Markelle Fultz",
         "choices": [
            "Lebron James",
            "Luka Doncic",
            "Markelle Fultz",
            "Oscar Robertson"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 20,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What year was the NBA created?",
         "answer": "1949",
         "choices": [
            "1920",
            "1949",
            "1952",
            "1961"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 21,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What university did Dwayne Wade attend?",
         "answer": "Marquette",
         "choices": [
            "Duke",
            "Boston College",
            "Georgia Tech",
            "Marquette"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 22,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "How many players to this date have made the jump from high school to the NBA?",
         "answer": "44",
         "choices": [
            "10",
            "22",
            "44",
            "75"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 23,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "How many championship rings does the Laker franchise have?",
         "answer": "16",
         "choices": [
            "18",
            "16",
            "15",
            "11"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 24,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "What is Shaquille O’neal’s career PPG average?",
         "answer": "23.7",
         "choices": [
            "19.5",
            "23.7",
            "27.3",
            "30.1"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 25,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Who scored the Toronto Raptors first ever franchise basket?",
         "answer": "Alvin Robertson",
         "choices": [
            "Damon Stoudamire",
            "Vince Carter",
            "Doug Christie",
            "Alvin Robertson"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 26,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who is the only player to average a triple double in the NBA finals?",
         "answer": "LeBron James",
         "choices": [
            "LeBron James",
            "Magic Johnson",
            "Larry Bird",
            "Oscar Robertson"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 27,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who was the only team to beat Michael Jordan in a series between 1991 and 1998?",
         "answer": "Orlando Magic",
         "choices": [
            "Houston Rockets",
            "Detroit Pistons",
            "Boston Celtics",
            "Orlando Magic"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 28,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "How many points did Reggie Miller score in the final 18.7 seconds of Game 1 against the New York Knicks in 1995?",
         "answer": "8",
         "choices": [
            "6",
            "8",
            "10",
            "12"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 29,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Which coach did Latrell Spreewell choke in practice?",
         "answer": "PJ Carlesimo",
         "choices": [
            "Flip Saunders",
            "Jeff Van Gundy",
            "PJ Carlesimo",
            "Don Nelson",
            "Eric Musselman"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 30,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Who did the Toronto Raptors trade in exchange to the rights for Vince Carter in 1998?",
         "answer": "Antawn Jamison",
         "choices": [
            "Mike Bibby",
            "Keon Clark",
            "Tyson Wheeler",
            "Bonzi Wells",
            "Antawn Jamison"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 31,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who won the 1997 rookie of the year?",
         "answer": "Allen Iverson",
         "choices": [
            "Marcus Camby",
            "Stephon Marbury",
            "Ray Allen",
            "Steve nash",
            "Allen Iverson",
            "Kobe Bryant"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 32,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who were the first team to be a #1 seed and lose to a #8 seed in the NBA playoffs?",
         "answer": "Seattle SuperSonics",
         "choices": [
            "LA Lakers",
            "Seattle SuperSonics",
            "Dallas mavericks",
            "Portland Trailblazers",
            "Milwaukee Bucks",
            "Denver Nuggets"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 33,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "When was the last time Kobe Byrant made all NBA first team?",
         "answer": "2012-13",
         "choices": [
            "2013-14",
            "2012-13",
            "2011-12",
            "2010-11"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 34,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "What two teams did Kareem Abdul-Jabbar play for?",
         "answer": "LA Lakers, Milwaukee Bucks",
         "choices": [
            "Baltimore Bullets, Seattle Supersonics",
            "LA Lakers, New York Knicks",
            "Milwauke Bucks, Houston Rockets",
            "LA Lakers, Milwaukee Bucks"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 35,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "What team originally drafted Brandon Roy in 2006?",
         "answer": "Minnesota Timberwolves",
         "choices": [
            "Minnesota Timberwolves",
            "Portland Trailblazers",
            "Indian Pacers",
            "Washington Wizards",
            "Toronto Raptors"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 36,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "1989 NBA Playoffs - Game 5 between the Chicago Bulls and Cleveland Cavaliers - Michael Jordan made what came to be known today as \"The Shot\". The Bulls were trailing by one point and had the ball with 3 seconds to go. Who did Jordan shoot over?",
         "answer": "Craig Ehlo",
         "choices": [
            "Craig Ehlo",
            "Ron Harper",
            "Steve Kerr",
            "Larry Nance",
            "Mark Price"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 37,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "What shoes was Jordan wearing when he made his first well known “game winner”?",
         "answer": "Jordan 4",
         "choices": [
            "Jordan 1",
            "Jordan 3",
            "Jordan 4",
            "Jordan 13"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 38,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Which of the following was a NBA scoring champ one year after being named Rookie of the Year?",
         "answer": "Dave Bing",
         "choices": [
            "Dave Bing",
            "Michael Jordan",
            "Lebron james",
            "Kobe Bryant"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 39,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What number did Scottie Pippen wear?",
         "answer": "33",
         "choices": [
            "23",
            "32",
            "33",
            "34",
            "43"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 40,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who won the 2005 NBA MVP?",
         "answer": "Steve Nash",
         "choices": [
            "Lebron James",
            "Kobe Bryant",
            "Steve Nash",
            "Dirk Nowitzki"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 41,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What player led the NBA in points per game during the 03-04 season?",
         "answer": "Tracy McGrady",
         "choices": [
            "Peja Stojakovic",
            "Kevin Garnett",
            "Kobe Bryant",
            "Tracy McGrady"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 42,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What year did LeBron James win his first MVP?",
         "answer": "2008-2009",
         "choices": [
            "2007-2008",
            "2006-2007",
            "2008-2009",
            "2010-2011"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 43,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who was the NBA’s first ever MVP in 1956?",
         "answer": "Bob Pettit",
         "choices": [
            "Bob Pettit",
            "George Mikan",
            "Bill Sharman",
            "Larry Foust"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 44,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What was LeBron James rookie stat line?",
         "answer": "20PPG-5APG-5RPG",
         "choices": [
            "18PPG-6APG-6RSP",
            "25PPG-5APG-6RPG",
            "20PPG-5APG-5RPG",
            "22PPG-8APG-5RPG"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 45,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who won MVP in 2008?",
         "answer": "Kobe Bryant",
         "choices": [
            "Chris Paul",
            "Steve Nash",
            "Dirk Nowitzki"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 46,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What team did Damian Lillard eliminate with an iconic game winner over Paul George?",
         "answer": "OKC thunder",
         "choices": [
            "Indiana Pacers",
            "LA Clippers",
            "OKC thunder",
            "Atlanta hawks"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 47,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "How many sixth man of the year awards has Jamal Crawford won?",
         "answer": "3",
         "choices": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 48,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Which player is the all time leader in points scored for the Memphis Grizzlies?",
         "answer": "Mike Conley",
         "choices": [
            "Marc Gasol",
            "Zach Randolph",
            "Pau Gasol",
            "Mike Conley"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 49,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": false,
         "question": "Which player was traded from the Toronto Raptors for Kawhi Leonard?",
         "answer": "DeMar DeRozen",
         "choices": [
            "Malachi Richardson",
            "DeMar DeRozen",
            "Delon Wright",
            "CJ Miles"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 50,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Which player scored 37 points in a single quarter?",
         "answer": "Klay Thompson",
         "choices": [
            "James Johnson",
            "Steph Curry",
            "James Harden",
            "Bradley Beal",
            "Klay Thompson"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 51,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "Who is the all time leader in points scored for the Toronto Raptors?",
         "answer": "DeMar DeRozan",
         "choices": [
            "DeMar DeRozan",
            "Vince Carter",
            "Chris Bosh",
            "Kawhi Leonard"
         ]
      },
      {
         "questionId": 52,
         "category": "basketball",
         "star": true,
         "question": "What is Dwayne Wade’s nickname?",
         "answer": "Flash",
         "choices": [
            "Lightning",
            "Speedy",
            "Invisible Man",
            "Flash"
         ]
      }
   ]
}